{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Electrophoresis is defined as the migration of _____to the ____charged electrode under the influence of an electric field",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Charged particles (ions), oppositely",
        "b": "Charged particles (ions), similarly",
        "c": "Uncharged particles (ions), oppositely",
        "d": "Either a or b"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. The electrophoretic mobility (μ) is the velocity of a macromolecule under a constant electric field. μ of a biomolecule is influenced by its",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Charge",
        "b": "Mass",
        "c": "Shape",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. SDS-PAGE is an electrophoretic technique commonly used for analysing ________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "DNA",
        "b": "RNA",
        "c": "Proteins",
        "d": "Lipids"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. In Polyacrylamide Gel Electrophoresis, proteins will migrate towards the ________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cathode or positive electrode",
        "b": "Anode or positive electrode",
        "c": "Cathode or negitive electrode",
        "d": "Anode or negitive electrode"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. In SDS-PAGE, the protein molecules are separated on the basis of",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Charge",
        "b": "Mass",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. To study a protein complex, which type of gel electrophoresis is preferred?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "SDS-PAGE",
        "b": "Native PAGE",
        "c": "Agarose gel electrophoresis",
        "d": "2D Gel Electrophoresis"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. In SDS-PAGE, _________ renders a uniform negative charge to the proteins.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Sodium dodecyl sulphate",
        "b": "Ammonium persulfate",
        "c": "Beta-mercaptoethanol",
        "d": "Both a and c"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Electrophoretic velocity (v) of the protein samples _________ with the increase in voltage.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "increases",
        "b": "decreases",
        "c": "remains unaffected",
        "d": "may increase of decrease"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. In reducing SDS-PAGE, _________ is used to break disulphide linkages in proteins.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "SDS",
        "b": "Both a and d",
        "c": "Heat",
        "d": "Beta-mercaptoethanol"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. To visualize the protein bands after separation using SDS-PAGE, which of the stains is used?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Coomassie Brilliant Blue staining",
        "b": "Ethidium bromide staining",
        "c": "Bromophenol blue staining",
        "d": "Xylene cyanol staining"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
   
  ]
}
